# **Varad Paralikar**

LeetCode:@varadsp\_ LinkedIn: @varadparalikar-38378a126 Portfolio: varadsp.github.io

Github: @VARADSP

+91 - 7499472067 parlikarvarad@gmail.com Aurangabad, Maharashtra, India

**SUMMARY** 

Dynamic Software Engineer with over 4 years of experience in full-stack development, particularly high-impact across various industries including SaaS products, CRM. Known for collaborative approach, strong problem-solving skills and proven success in the application development lifecycle.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Zoho Corporation (Chennai, India) | Member Of Technical Staff

Jul 2021 - Present

- Working on live Zoho CRM Product having over 100 million customers worldwide.
- Making performance improvements in the product, debugging, bug fixing, configuration changes, feature development and enhancement involving internal frameworks, Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Microservices, Spring Boot, ORM, Struts2 MVC framework.
- Built a standalone feature for Zoho CRM's Sandbox deployment flow using Java, REST APIs, Kafka and Backend flow. Led a performance optimization team project, enhancing API efficiency by 20% using Java flame graphs and Redis cache.
- Tech Stack: Java, JS, OOP, Spring Boot, Struts, MVC, SaaS, Kafka, REST, CI/CD, PostgreSQL, Git, Backend

# Unikaihatsu Software Pvt. Ltd. (Ahmedabad, India) | Full Stack Engineer

Jun 2019 - Sep 2020

- Worked on live Japanese projects involving Spring framework, iBatis ORM, DTO, DAO, MVC architecture with frontend involving JSP, Javascript, JQuery, CSS.
- Solving bugs and developing the project to meet with Japanese clients requirements.
- Developing native apps, chat feature in flutter, dart with JSON data for clients requirements.
- Tech Stack: Java, JS, OOP, Spring Boot, MVC, Flutter, Dart, REST, CI/CD, Microservices, Tortoise SVN, MySQL

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering**

Jan 2015 - Jun 2019

• Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Marathwada University, Percentage: 79%

# **PROJECTS**

# **Lab Sharing Using Docker**

Feb 2019 - Feb 2019

- Worked as an equal member of a four members team to develop webapp for sharing docker containers over the network in lab infrastructure. This project provides students the GUI based containers having different tools such as RStudio, Eclipse, SciLab, Java, etc for lab practices.
- Web app manages user space with session management and user's data is saved using volume sharing.MySQL database is used to manage container requests and serve them. Using port forwarding containers were mapped to client browsers.
- Github Link: https://github.com/VARADSP/Lab-Sharing-Using-Docker
- Tech stack : Docker, Linux, PHP, Html, CSS, Javascript, JQuery

# **Flutter App Memorizer**

Mar 2021 - Apr 2021

- A flutter project designed with Firebase, Firestore as backend hosted with Firebase hosting.
- The web is implemented with multiple functionalities such as saving users Notes, chatting with friends, maintaining story board, making advance calculations etc.
- Github Link: <a href="https://github.com/VARADSP/Memorizer-A-Flutter-Web-App">https://github.com/VARADSP/Memorizer-A-Flutter-Web-App</a>
- Tech Stack: Flutter, Dart, JSON, Firebase, Git, Mobile Development

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS**

• Participated in Smart India Hackathon 2018, In the category of Tribal Ministry, Assam, Worked as a mentor for the team throughout the event, developing sports events android app for the rural region .

# **CERTIFICATIONS AND TEST SCORES**

- Competitive Programming at LeetCode, HackerRank (https://www.hackerrank.com/spartaclub86?hr r=1)
- Completed Linux Certifications RHCSA,RHCE (Redhat Certifications), JLPT N5 (Japanese Language)

#### **SKILLS**

- DevOps: Linux, Git, Github, Ansible, Docker, Maven, CI/CD, Logs, Monitoring
- Frontend: Javascript, JQuery, HTML/CSS
- Backend: Java, Spring Boot, MVC, JPA, Struts, Debugging, OOP, Data Structures, Algorithms, System Design
- Database: MySQL, Postgres, Firebase, SQL, NOSQL, ORM Frameworks (Hibernate, iBatis, Zoho Mickey)